我们想获得共享代码片段的能力,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: We wanna get
the ability to share code snippets,
因为这是文档主题，对吧？
because it's docs theme, right?
因此，文档名称的一个常见用例是共享代码。
And so a very common use case for
docs name is gonna be to share code.
所以，接下来我们要做的就是建立一个语法突显。
So, the next thing we're gonna do
is set up a syntax highlighting.
为了做到这一点，我们将安装一些小助手。
And to do that, we're going to
install a couple little helpers.
所以让我们来做纱线工作室，盖茨比主题码头和
So let's do yarn workspace,
gatsby-theme-docks and
我们要添加棱镜反应渲染器。
we're going to add
the prism-react-renderer.
然后我们将使用 mdx-utils，这将帮助我们处理一些繁忙的
And then we're going to use mdx-utils,
which will help us handle some busy
使反应渲染器正常工作的工作。
work of making the react
renderer work properly.
一旦安装完成，我们就可以进入文档了
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Once those
are installed, we can go in to our docs
我们将在组件中创建一个新文件，称为 code。
package, and we'll create a new file
in components, that is called code.
我们用这个作为我们的代码高亮,
And we're gonna use this as
our kind of code highlighting,
语法突显元素。
syntax highlighting element.
所以，让我们设置它使用主题-ui,
So, let's set it up to use theme-ui,
所以从 theme-ui 导入 jsx
so import jsx from theme-ui, and
然后我们从 mdx-utils 导入 pretocodelock。
then we're going to import
preToCodeBlock From mdx-utils.
这样我们就可以从 pre 元素中得到一些支持
And this will allow us to get some
props out of the pre element and
把引擎盖下面的东西换了一下
switch some things up under the hood, so
它与棱镜反应渲染器兼容。
that it's compatible with
the prism react renderer.
然后我们要导入高光部分和一些默认道具。
Then we're going to import the highlight
component and some default props.
来自 prism-react-renderer。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: From
prism-react-renderer.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 最后,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And finally,
我要从 prism-react-renderer / themes 导入一个主题
I'm gonna import a theme from
prism-react-renderer/themes and
我想要的是《夜奔》 ，这是莎拉 · 德拉斯纳的主题。
the one that I want is nightOwl
which is Sarah Drasner's theme.
这也是我们今天在编辑器中使用的。
It's also the one that we're
using in the editor today.
这是我的最爱。
It's my favorite.
现在我们有了这个，我们就有能力展示这些东西
So now that we've got this we have
the ability to start showing the stuff, so
让我们创建一个名为 code 的组件。
let's create a component called code.
这将会得到一些支持
And that's gonna receive some props and
里面我们可以做，我们的代码道具将要,
inside we can do,
our code props are going to,
这就是我们在道具上使用 pretocodelock 的地方。
this is where we use that
preToCodeBlock on our props.
所以这就给了我们，什么语言是前
And so what this is doing is it's giving
us like what language is the the pre
块使用。
block using.
代码字符串是否与标记的其余部分分开
Do we have the the code string separated
from the rest of the the markup
前置块。
of the pre block.
这让我们的生活更加轻松。
And that just makes our
lives a little bit easier.
所以我们要做的第一件事就是如果我们没有任何代码道具,
So the first thing we're gonna do
is if we didn't get any code props,
那就不是高级代码块了。
then it's not a highlightable code block.
因为有可能有人只是用它来显示块文本，或者
Because there is a chance that somebody's
just using it to show block text, or
这是引用，不一定是代码。
that it's a quote, and
not necessarily code.
如果是这样的话，我们就返回一个前置标签。
And if that's the case,
we're just gonna return a pre tag.
然后把原来的道具送进去。
And send in the original props.
这就是我们的紧急援助。
So that's our bailout.
如果我们没有得到任何代码道具回来，我们只是发回默认的前技术。
If we don't get any code props back,
we just send back at default pre tech.
如果我们有代码道具，我们会把其中一些拿出来。
If we do have code props,
we're gonna pull some of those out.
所以我们需要代码字符串和特定的语言。
So we want the code string and
the language specifically.
我们从代码道具中得到这些。
And we get those out of the code props.
然后，我们要退回一些东西。
Then, we are gonna return some stuff.
现在，这是一个看起来有点早的部分。
And now, this is a little bit
of an early looking component.
先警告你一下这可能会有点棘手
So just fair warning,
this is gonna get a little hairy, but
当它起作用的时候很酷。
it's very cool when it works.
所以我们从这个高光开始。
So we start out by using this highlight.
在这里面，我们要分散默认的道具。
And inside of it we are going
to spread out the default props.
因此，如果所有其他方法都失败了，它将出现一些默认值，并且
So that if all else fails,
it will have some defaults and
至少看起来没有完全崩溃。
at least not look completely broken.
然后我们将代码设置为代码字符串。
Then we're gonna set
the code to the codestring.
我们要把语言设置成。
We're gonna set the language
to the language.
我们将把主题设置为主题。
And we'll set the theme to the theme.
这一个使用渲染道具模式，这意味着我们得到一个函数返回。
This one uses the render props pattern,
which means that we get a function back.
在这个函数中，我们可以做一些事情。
And inside of that
function we can do things.
在这个渲染道具里面的道具，就是这个类的名字,
The, the props that will get in
this render prop, is the classname,
是一个辅助函数,
style, tokens,
getLineProps which is a helper function,
和 getTokenProps 也是辅助函数。
and getTokenProps with
is also helper function.
我们才刚刚开始。
And we are just getting started.
然后我们会发布一个。
So then we are gonna put out a pre.
这一个有一个类名为 className。
And this one has a class
name of className.
然后它将使用一种风格，单数和
And then it's going to use
a style of style,singular and
然后我们要添加一点帮助器，以确保它看起来类似。
then we want to add a little bit of helper
to make sure that it looks similar to it.
我们只是希望它在我们的主题看起来漂亮。
We just want it to look nice in our theme.
所以我们要拍一下
And so we're gonna have
a little bit of patting and
然后如果代码块是长的，我们要滚动，而不是在流和
then if the code block is long,
we want to scroll, not over flow and
最后我要在这里用一个变体放一个钩子。
finally I'm gonna put a hook
in here using a variant.
现在我们还没有研究变体。
Now we haven't looked at variants yet.
我们稍后会讲到更多的细节，但是
We'll get into those in a little more
detail a little bit later on but
这些都是一个有效的命名方式，有人覆盖样式
what these are is effectively a named
way for someone to override styles in
主题-ui 配置，我们添加这种方便的事情。
the theme-ui config which we're adding
this as kind of a convenience thing.
如果有人使用此主题并希望覆盖棱镜突出显示样式。
If somebody uses this theme and wants
to override the prism highlight styles.
他们可以通过在他们的主题 UI 配置中声明一个棱镜高亮道具来实现,
They can do it by declaring a prism
highlight prop in their theme UI config,
而不是注入这个组件
instead of having to
inject this component and
处理我们在这里制造的混乱。
deal with all of this kind of
clutter that we're creating here.
所以，一旦我们进入 pre，然后我们将映射我们的代币。
So, once we're inside our pre,
then we're going to map over our tokens.
第一个给我们一条线，然后是索引，对吗？
And the first one is going to give us
the line and then it's index, right?
在这里面，我们要展开 getline 道具的结果
And inside of this we're going to
spread out the results of getline props
因为我们需要得到这些，它是一个物体。
because we need to get those and
it's an object.
所以我们在线上传递，然后关键是索引和
So we pass in line, and
then the key is gonna be the index and
这给了我们一个独一无二的钥匙。
that just gives us a unique key for it.
然后，在这里面，我们要
Then, inside of that, we're going to
地图上的线路本身，这将给我们一个信号和一个关键。
map over the line itself and
that's going to give us a token and a key.
最后我们得到了一个跨度。
And finally we get a span.
这个跨度将得到 tokenProps。
And this span is going
to get the tokenProps.
这里的值是令牌和密钥。
And the values there are the token and
the key.
有人的大脑从耳朵里融化出来了吗？
Okay, has anybody's brain
melted out of their ears yet?
这是一个，像大毛发成分。
This is a, like big hairy component.
所以，我们正在做一些事情。
So, we're doing several things.
我们首先将它包装在一般的高亮组件中,
We start by just wrapping it in
the general highlight component,
这是一个棱镜反应渲染器类型的嘿,
that's a prism react
renderers kind of hey,
让我们设置荧光笔工作所需的所有默认值。
let's set all the defaults that we
need for the highlighter to work.
然后，我们在这里得到所有这些默认值，并创建一个 pre 标记。
Then, We get all these defaults
in here and create a pre tag.
荧光笔的工作原理是，把线分开。
And then the way that a highlighter
works is it breaks the string apart.
所以不仅仅是你的代码块,
So it's not just, your code block,
然后你会得到一堆带有代码的字符串。
and then you get a bunch
of string with code in it.
它接受这段代码，并将其分解成所有这些标记。
It takes that code and
it breaks it up into all these tokens.
这里有关键词，这里有线，这里有各种各样的东西。
So there's keywords, there's lines,
there's all sorts of stuff like that.
我们首先获取令牌并将它们分解成行。
We start by taking the tokens and
breaking them into lines.
每一行都是它自己的 div。
Each line is its own div.
这使我们能够做一些事情，比如给线编号，或者
That gives us the ability to do
things like number the lines, or
做斑马条纹，使它更容易跟踪，或突出线。
do zebra striping to make it easier
to track, or highlighting lines.
然后，在线的内部，我们必须得到令牌。
Then, inside of the line,
we have to get the token.
如果我们看一下高亮显示是如何工作的,
If we look at the way that
highlighting is working here,
我们可以看到支架是一种颜色。
we can see that the bracket is one color.
变量是另一种颜色，函数是另一种颜色。
The variable is another color,
the function is yet another color.
所以这些东西实际上都被分解成了一个标记，我们就是那个标记
So each of these things is actually
broken up into a token that we are then
包装在一个跨度中，这使得棱镜可以突出它。
wrapping in a span,
which allows prism to highlight it.
所以要让这个过程成功，还有两个步骤。
So to make this work
there are two more steps.
首先我们要在盖茨比插件的主题界面中,
The first thing is we're going to
in the Gatsby plug in theme UI,
我们可以指定组件的用途
we can specify what
components get used for
一个给定的 MDX HTML 值。
a given MDX HTML value.
所以我们可以把它作为一个前置标签
So we can over ride what
it gets as a pre tag which
我们可以通过使用 fence block 或者只是写一个 HTML pre 标签来创建。
we would create by using fence blocks or
just writing an HTML pre tag.
我们可以告诉它，无论何时你得到这些使用其他东西在它的地方。
We can tell it whenever you get one of
these use something else in its place.
所以我们通过创建一个 components.js 组件来实现这一点。
So we do that by creating
a components.js components.
确保它是 yes，它是复数 components.js。
Make sure it's yes it is
plural components.js.
我们正在盖茨比插件主题 UI 中实现这一点。
And we're doing that inside of
the Gatsby plugin theme UI.
所以来源。
So source.
盖茨比插件主题 UI 组件。
Gatsby plugin theme UI components.
然后在里面，我们可以导入我们的代码
And then inside of that,
we can import our code
组件代码组件。
component from components code.
然后我们导出一个对象
And then we just export an object, and
我们告诉 MDX，任何时候它遇到一个 pre 标记来使用那个代码组件。
we tell MDX that anytime it encounters
a pre tag to use that code component.
所以，在完成这些之后，现在我们可以获得一些代码。
So, with that being done,
now we can take some code.
所以让我把这个拷贝出来，我们可以进入我们的一个页面。
So let me just copy this out, and we can
go into one of our pages and I'm going to.
添加一些代码,
Add some code,
把它放在一个有 js 语言标签的栅栏里。
put it inside of a fenced block
with the js language tag.
在拯救这一切的同时
And upon saving this and
在启动服务器时，Jason Lengstorf: 我们应该
starting the server,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: We should
可以看到一些突出显示的代码 Jason Lengstorf:
be able to see some highlighted code
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Did I
忘记输出密码了？
forget to export the code?
我做了，所以我们要导出默认代码
I did, so
we're going to export default code
从代码组件，这应该能解决我们的问题。
from the code component and
that should solve our problem.
好了。
There we go.
现在我们可以得到任何代码
So now we're getting any
code that we drop in
都会附加特定的朗格语高亮。
gets langauge specific
highlighting attached to it.
如果我们添加一些其他的东西，比如我进入这个 index.js，不管它在哪里。
And if we add something else, like if I
go into this index.js, wherever it was.
我补充一点，比如说，杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 是的
And I add, let's say some,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: It's
我不会强调这一点，所以就别管它了。
not gonna try to highlight that,
so it'll just leave it alone.
好了，现在我们可以保存我们的工作了。
Okay so now we can save our work.
所以我们添加了一些新的包，创建了这些代码,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: So we added some
new packages, created that code,
组件添加了这个代码组件作为 pre 标记的覆盖
component added that code component
as a override for the pre tag
在 gatsby-plugin-theme UI 中，为我们的索引 mdx 添加了一些 fence 代码块。
in gatsby-plugin-theme UI added some
fence code blocks to our index mdx.